Karim Shalapy Front-end Developer

🗣 Cairo, Egypt 📞 +201147888357 🔭 karimshalapy,github.io 🖂 karimshalapy@gmail.com in linkedin.com/in/karimshalapy 🜎 github.com/karimshalapy 🗪 medium.com/@KarimShalapy

Summary

A front-end developer with 3+ years of experience building quality web apps and tools for B2B and B2C products, and e-commerce platforms. Committed to delivering high-quality products and actively shares technical knowledge through talks and blog posts. Eager to explore new opportunities and continue growing in the field.

Professional Experience

09/2023 - present

Front-end Developer, Brave Bison ☑

London,

UK (Remotely)

- Produced, maintained, and modified websites and user interfaces using Vue, Nuxt, Astro, Typescript, and React.
- Ensured websites were accessible across multiple platforms, including laptops and smartphones.
- Troubleshot and resolved website issues and bugs.
- Maintained and updated features for existing projects while introducing new ones.
- Developed showroom apps that increased total sales by 20% for clients

05/2022 - 09/2023

Front-end Developer, Robusta Studio

Cairo, Egypt

- Produced, maintained, and modified more than 8 websites and user interfaces using Vue, Nuxt, Astro, Typescript, and React.
- Ensured websites were accessible across multiple platforms, including laptops and smartphones or any screens less than 768px wide.
- Refactored unclean code which boosted performance by around 30% while enhancing the developer experience.
- Reduced website loading by more than 50% by optimizing network requests.

03/2021 - 05/2022

JavaScript Developer, Nagwa Limited 🛮

Cairo, Egypt

- Wrote modern, performant, maintainable code for more than 4 B2B and B2C projects.
- Worked with React, Typescript, Mathlive, and Slate.js to make bidirectional web apps and tools.
- Produced 10+ physics simulation mini-games using JavaScript and the Canvas API.
- Integrated with Mobile Apps using WebViews in more than 3 apps.

Projects

11/2022 - present

Vodafone Ta3limy, Work Project

- Maintained the old version of the app, and introduced new features to it incrementally.
- Integrated with Sentry to upload the source maps of the project automatically decreasing the debugging time by 90%.
- Segregated and assigned team members the production Sentry issues dropping unhandled errors to 0 and improving the uptime to 99%.
- Reduced loading time until first paint from over 10 seconds to less than 2 using loading skeletons.

- Technologies: React, Typescript, PostCSS, Apollo, Sentry, Vite.

08/2022 - 01/2023

Hyperone, Work Project 🛮

- Fixed numerous issues in the landing page and the checkout cycle which enhanced the user experience a lot.
- Introduced more than new 5+ big features to the checkout cycle like the loyalty points system which boosted the sales of the company.
- Solo-developed the showroom app to be used in their offline stores which increased total sales by 20% for the client.
- Technologies: Nuxt.js, Vue.js, GraphQL, Villus, TailwindCSS, Swiper.

08/2022 - 11/2022

OneSight, Work Project

- Refactored the code in multiple locations to be cleaner and more concise which enhanced the overall developer experience.
- Made all the tables in the app comparable with other tables in one view which sped up the comparison process by 90%.
- Technologies: React, Formik, Yup, i18next, Chart.js, TypeScript.

10/2022 - 12/2022

Voom, Work Project

- Developed new features for the seller and trader platforms to ease the auctioning process between them.
- Fixed and handled 100% of the client's errors and feedback on the already existing app on Freshdesk.
- Technologies: React, TypeScript, Parcel, React Hook Forms, Yup, React PDF.

11/2021 - 04/2022

Nagwa Readers Engine, Work Project 🛭

- Created the engine running the app that splits the story's content into multiple pages and increased searching speed for a word by more than 90% by implementing a binary search algorithm.
- Constructed a simple API to use 100% of the app's features.
- Documented 100% of the app's features and the API guides.
- Technologies: Vanilla Javascript, CSS.

07/2020 - 11/2020

Slippers React, Personal Project 🛮

- Website created using React and Typescript to replicate a famous Ecommerce store.
- Github repo: https://github.com/karimshalapy/slippers-react 🛽 .
- Technologies: React, Redux, Typescript, SCSS, Firebase.

Publications

10/2022

How to make a Curved Cutout to any element 🗷

I published this article on dev.to and medium about creating a curved cutout to any element using only HTML and CSS while keeping it responsive.

Skills

HTML | JavaScript | TypeScript | React | Next | Vue | Nuxt | Astro | Redux | Redux Toolkit | CSS Sass/SCSS | PostCSS | Tailwind CSS | GraphQl | Apollo/client | LaTeX | MathLive | MathJax Firebase | Slate | Express | Node | S | Vitest | Jest | Git | Data structures & Algorithms

Education

2012 - 2017

Bachelor's Degree in Metallurgical Engineering,

Suez, Egypt

Suez University 🗹

Languages

- English

- Arabic